LA'TONIA MERTICA SHEPPARD WALKER

writer | photographer { full stack developer } videographer | designer

2200 S Salina St #684 Syracuse NY 13205 | 315.810.8098 | latoniamertica@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/latoniamertica

OBJECTIVE

Full Stack Javascript Developer with specialization in **Python** and **design**. A position that supports consistent use of **CSS**, **HTML**, **Javascript**, **React**, **SQL**, **ORM**, and **Github**. Incorporates my experience in **Adobe Suite** – with focus on **Indesign**, **Photoshop**, and **Premiere Pro**. While encouraging diverse continued learning for holistic growth.

EXPERIENCE

Communications Manager

CenterState CEO Syracuse Surge - aka The Surge

09/2021 - present

Collaborate with partners that include staff at City of Syracuse and CenterState CEO to co-plan, implement, and execute **strategic communications**. Manage partners and contractors to generate content, produce deliverables, and deploy earned media efforts with mission to increase public understanding and access to initiatives while increasing relevance through news and other communication channels (ie. web; social media; email marketing; print; marketing collateral; video; broadcast; advertising; etc.)

Founder & Executive Officer

La'Tonia Mertica 'Communications & Creatives Specialist'

09/2019 - present

B2B communication services focusing on exceptional internal and external processes that result in exceptional communications and creatives. Such as detailed consults that reflect how to holistically present one's small business as best they can online and off, in-house and out. Including:

- Brand, voice, and identity establishment, fine tuning, and evolution
- Content generation and curation (ie. stock pix/vix; graphic design)
- Social media setup and temporary management
- Landing page development and landing/home page redevelopment
- Efficiency consultation for elevated reuse, editing, and/or repurposing

Marketing Team Intern

Full Bodied Health 'Nutrition for The Health You Deserve'

11/2020 - 01/2021

Brainstorm, outline, and implement ideas/strategies to enhance brand, and increase awareness, engagement, revenue, and content availability – responsibilities also involved website dressing/creation.

EDUCATION

Columbia University Justice Through Code **Python** Bootcamp
Hack Upstate Careers in Code **Full Stack Javascript** Code/Web Dev Bootcamp
Syracuse University Dual Degree BS/Newspaper and BA/Psychology

COMMISSION

Notary Public, Onondaga County, New York State

